Draper Corporation Photographs 6612 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:1023-1046, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1033: Houses on Bancroft Parkway, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1033. 1891-1900]. Image depicts three two-story wooden homes facing an unpaved street. Each home has two chimneys and shutters at each window, and two entrances; all are duplexes. The house in the center right is in the Dutch Colonial style. These houses were constructed for Draper Company employees. Other homes can be glimpsed in the background. See Box 2, Folder 2, Item 171 for these same houses seen from the opposite angle. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1035: Adin Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1035. 1891-1900. Image depicts the unpaved Adin Street in Hopedale, Massachusetts, a wide street with one house glimpsed on the right. Telephone or telegraph poles line the street on the left, but the area on the left appears unsettled. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25.25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1036: Draper Company: Screw shop chimney, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1036. 1891-1895. Image depicts a chimney surrounded by scaffolding; construction appears to be completed as the rounded edge of the chimney can be seen at the top. Workmen are posing at the top of the scaffolding. A roof with skylights is in the bottom foreground; both skylights and chimney are part of the Draper Co.'s machine screw shop. See Box 1, Folder 7, Item 1055 for another view of this chimney near completion from a different angle. 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Item 1037: Hopedale, Massachusetts: fire service test, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1037. 1891-1895. Image depicts a scene along a river or pond. Fire hoses are connected to a hydrant in the right foreground and water is being sprayed in an upward arc, falling into the water. A wooden clapboard building (possibly a storehouse of some kind?) is on the left and homes can be seen in the background on the opposite shore. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1040: Another view of drafting room, Draper Co., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1040. 1895? Image depicts another view of the drafting room at the Draper Company in Hopedale, Massachusetts (see also Box 1, Folder 7, Item 1051 for a different angle). An easel is visible in the foreground with another to the right. A rolltop desk is in the center of the room, in front of a very large, three-pane window that allows plenty of natural light. What appears to be a shuttered window in the background on the right. A multiple-lamp fixture, all shaded, hangs from the ceiling and other hanging fixtures provide light as well. The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Massachusetts, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1041: Draper Company: Milling Marsh #4, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1041. 1891-1895. Image depicts a piece of machinery photographed in front of a white sheet, indicating that it may have been intended for promotional use. [See Item 1042, in this folder, for another view of the machine.] 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1042: Draper Company: Milling Marsh #4, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1042. 1891-1895. Image depicts a piece of machinery photographed in front of a white sheet, indicating that it may have been intended for promotional use. [See Item 1041, in this folder, for another view of the machine.] 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1043: Hopedale, Massachusetts: houses in Bancroft Park, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1043. 1891-1895. Image depicts two two-story wood-shingled homes facing an unpaved street. Each home has two chimneys and shutters at each window. The house on the left has two entrances and is clearly a two-family. The house on the right is also probably a two-family, although the entrance on the far right cannot be seen. Other homes are partially visible in the background and on the right. Brand new spindly trees have been planted along the edge of the sidewalk; they are barely visible. A clothes line can be seen in the rear yard on the left. See Item 1032 and Item 1033, in this folder, for other views of Bancroft Park houses. These dwellings were most likely constructed by the Draper Co. for their employees. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1044: Hopedale, Massachusetts: aerial view of Hopedale looking southeast along Hopedale Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1044. 1891-1895. Image depicts Draper Company office building in lower left corner, along with two other mill buildings in center and on the right. Beyond Draper buildings are other businesses and residences. Not the same view seen in Item 1026, in this folder. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1045: Draper Company: four male workers in interior of shop, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1045. 1891-1895. Image depicts four male workers posing in what may have been a woodworking shop. A wooden box sits on a bench in front of them, with a wooden basket partially visible on the left. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1046: Draper Company: Radial drill attachment, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1046. 1891-1895. Image depicts a piece of machinery. Other equipment is also viewed in background. 20.5 x 25 cm.
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:1047-1066, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1047: Draper Company: chimney under construction, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1047. 1891-1895. Image depicts a chimney surrounded and topped by scaffolding. Two other shorter chimneys and mill buildings are visible in the background. Piles of bricks and other construction materials are on the ground in the foreground. See Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1003 and Item1004, Box 1, Folder 6, Item 1036, and Item 1055, in this folder, for other views of this chimney under construction. 20.5 x 25 cm.
  - Item 1048: Hopedale, Massachusetts: laying sewer pipe, Main Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1048. 1891-1895. Image depicts a trench running along the center of a residential street ready for sewer pipes to be installed. Homes are visible on both sides of the street; note the hanging laundry on the left. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1049: Guild fair, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1049. 1891-1895. Image depicts a view of two booths set up for a guild fair. Shutters in room are closed; poles are wrapped in fabric or material, such as maypoles would be decorated. It is unclear if this guild fair was held at the Draper Company location or elsewhere. See also Item 1050, Item 1052, and Item 1053, in this folder, for other views of this guild fair. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1050: Guild fair, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1050. 1891-1895. Image depicts a view of two booths set up for a guild fair. One is completely surrounded by curtains; the other has hanging drapes pulled back. Poles in the room are wrapped in fabric or material, such as maypoles would be decorated. It is unclear if this guild fair was held at the Draper Company location or elsewhere. See also Item 1049, Item 1052, and Item 1053, in this folder, for other views of this guild fair. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1051: Drafting room, Draper Co., black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1051. 1895? Image depicts a view of the drafting room at the Draper Company in Hopedale, Massachusetts Several easels/drafting tables are in the room, along with two chairs and a stool. A row of cabinets lines the back wall. A chandelier with shaded bulbs hangs from the ceiling and other hanging fixtures provide light as well. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Item 1040, in this folder, Box 1, Folder 4, Item 999 and Box 1, Folder 3, Item 44 for other views of the drafting room. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1052: Guild fair, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1052. 1891-1895. Image depicts a view of a large booth set up for a guild fair. Hanging sheer draperies have been pulled back to simulate a canopy top and are fastened with large butterflies. Two long tables have been placed at an angle to each other with a small circular table in the center filling in to complete the booth. Two portraits on the back wall have also been decorated. It is unclear if this guild fair was held at the Draper Company location or elsewhere. See also Item 1049, Item 1050, and Item 1053, in this folder, for other views of this guild fair. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1053: Guild fair, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1053. 1891-1895. Image depicts a view of a booth, piano, and curtain decorated for a guild fair; the booth appears to be set up to sell or dispense cake and ice cream. Shutters in room are closed; poles are wrapped in fabric or material, such as maypoles would be decorated. It is unclear if this guild fair was held at the Draper Company location or elsewhere. See also Item 1049, Item 1050, and Item 1052, in this folder, for other views of this guild fair. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1054: Mrs. Southwick's house on Freedom Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1054. 1891-1895. Image depicts two-story wooden home with gabled roof, three chimneys, and shutters at each window. The front porch is covered with ivy, as is a small portion of the side of the house. A sidewalk runs between the house and the unpaved street. Another home is partially visible on the right. It is not known who Mrs. Southwick was. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 1055: Draper Company: Chimney construction, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1055. 1891-1895. Image depicts a chimney under construction surrounded by scaffolding, possibly the screw shop chimney. Construction appears to be near completion. Workmen are posed at the top of the scaffolding. See also Item 1036, in this folder, for another view of what is apparently the same chimney from a different angle. 20.25 x 25 cm.
  - Item 1056: Union Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1056. 1891-1895. Image depicts an unpaved street with houses and yards visible on both sides. Union Street is crossed at a 90 degree angle by another street that also has houses on it. Union Street continues well into the distant background, going down a hill once past the cross street. See also Item 1057, in this folder. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 20.25 x 25 cm.
  - Item 1057: Houses on Union Street, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1057. 1891- 1895. Image depicts an unpaved street with small, wood-framed houses on either side. These houses were probably constructed as employee housing by the Draper Company. A railroad crossing can be seen in the center background, with a large wooden barn-type structure on the left and a two-story commercial building on the right. Union Street extends beyond the railroad crossing, with trees lining the street far into the distance. This is possibly the other end of the street seen in Item 1056, in this folder. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 20.25 x 25.25 cm.
  - Item 1058: Draper Company: threaders, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1058. 1891-1895. Image depicts a row of threading machines. Other equipment is viewed in the background. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1059: Looking south from Roper House, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1059. 1891-1895. Image depicts a winter scene, showing trees and snow on the ground. Image presumably taken from upper story of Roper House. The Charles Roper house was located at 50 Freedom Street in Hopedale. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1060: Looking southwest from Roper House, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1060. 1891-1895. Image depicts a winter scene, showing trees and snow on the ground, and a picket fence running the length of the property, with several houses partially visible on the right. Most of the scene is forested. The Charles Roper house was located at 50 Freedom Street in Hopedale. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1061: Hopedale, Massachusetts looking southwest from Social Streetachusetts, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1061. 1891-1895. Image depicts complex of multiple-story mill buildings in the foreground, most likely part of the Draper Company. Other town streets, railroad cars on tracks, and open fields are visible in the background. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.5 cm.
  - Item 1062: Draper Company: Experiment room, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from film negative no.A1062.2. April 21, 1892. Image depicts six men posed in a workroom. Two men are dressed in suits and ties; one wears a bowler hat and another bowler hat sits on a workshelf nearby. Two men are dressed in white shirts with vests and ties; the other two men are dressed in work clothes. The room contains a number of looms, some with batteries visible. It is unclear what "experiment room" refers to, but perhaps different aspects of the machinery were explored to see how they might work better or differently. Film negative 25 x 20.5 cm. Copy A.
  - Item 1062: Draper Company: Experiment room, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from film negative no.A1062.3. April 21, 1892. Image depicts six men posed in a workroom. Two men are dressed in suits and ties; one wears a bowler hat and another bowler hat sits on a workshelf nearby. Two men are dressed in white shirts with vests and ties; the other two men are dressed in work clothes. The room contains a number of looms, some with batteries visible. It is unclear what "experiment room" refers to, but perhaps different aspects of the machinery were explored to see how they might work better or differently. Film negative 25 x 20.5 cm. Copy B.
  - Item 1062: Draper Company: Experiment room, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from film negative no.A1062.4. April 21, 1892. Image depicts six men posed in a workroom. Two men are dressed in suits and ties; one wears a bowler hat and another bowler hat sits on a workshelf nearby. Two men are dressed in white shirts with vests and ties; the other two men are dressed in work clothes. The room contains a number of looms, some with batteries visible. It is unclear what "experiment room" refers to, but perhaps different aspects of the machinery were explored to see how they might work better or differently. Film negative 25 x 20.5 cm. Copy C.
  - Item 1062: Draper Company: Experiment room, 1892; black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from film positive no.A1062.5. April 21, 1892. Image depicts six men posed in a workroom. Two men are dressed in suits and ties; one wears a bowler hat and another bowler hat sits on a workshelf nearby. Two men are dressed in white shirts with vests and ties; the other two men are dressed in work clothes. The room contains a number of looms, some with batteries visible. It is unclear what "experiment room" refers to, but perhaps different aspects of the machinery were explored to see how they might work better or differently. Film positive 25 x 20.5 cm. Copy D.
  - Item 1063: Hopedale, Massachusetts: houses in Bancroft Park, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1063. 1891-1895. Image depicts a series of two-story wooden homes facing an unpaved street. The house in the center left has at least three chimneys and two entrances; it is most likely a duplex. It features Tudor-style timbering in the gables. The next house to the right has one front porch but may have two entrances; however, only one chimney is visible. The next house on the right has two entrances, one of each side of the front of the house, and, again, has at least three chimneys. The last house on the right has two entrances and two chimneys. These four homes consist of two different styles, but within each style there are a few differences. A few other houses are partially visible in the background. All were most likely constructed by the Draper Company for company employees. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1064: Hopedale Stable office, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1064. 1891- 1895. Image depicts a view of a small, single-story clapboard building, with a man standing in the entrance. What appears to be a two-story residential house is in the right background, behind a picket fence; other buildings can be seen in the left background, also behind a picket fence. There is some snow on the ground and the trees are bare. The sign on the post in the foreground reads: This is a Private Way Dangerous Passing. The stables themselves are presumably located outside the image. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 1065: Temple Shop, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1065. 1891-1895. Image depicts a view of the Temple Shop at the Draper Company in Hopedale, Massachusetts The view shows a counter along the windows on the right and machinery, including lathes, on the left. A temple is a device on a loom located near the fell of the cloth, one on each side; temples hold the cloth out as wide as possible during the process of weaving and prevent it from being drawn in too much by the filling. See Box 1, Folder 5, Item 1000 for a view of the Temple Shop with a dozen employees and taken from the opposite angle as this one. The Temple Shop was built in 1868 for W. W. Dutcher. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Box 1, Folder 5, Item 994 for a very similar shot. 20.25 x 25 cm.
  - Item 1066: Hopedale, Massachusetts: Knoff house, black and white photograph (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A1066. 1891-1895. Image depicts a two-story clapboard house with two chimneys. Shutters are closed over windows. A picket fence separates the home and yard from a tree-lined sidewalk and unpaved street. Part of the fence appears to cross a driveway. There is a shed in the backyard. A stepladder leans against the tree in the center foreground. It is not known who Knoff refers to. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 25 x 20.25 cm.
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:101-140: box no. 11-12, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Item 119: Prospect Heights, units 7-14, Milford, Massachusetts, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A119. 1901-1916? Image depicts a view of units 7 through 14 at Prospect Heights in Milford, Massachusetts The units are connected townhouse style, with eight separate entrances, and are made out of brick. The entire building is two stories with a small window visible in the third story on each end. There are chimneys on each end, in the middle, and two in the rear. Grass plots line the front, separated by walkways to each entrance. A large grassy area is in the foreground. Freestanding clotheslines are visible in the background at each end. These units were built for Draper Company employees and are believed to have been designed by Peabody & Stearns. See Box 3, Folder 2, Item 346 for what appears to be another view of this same housing. 25 x 20.25 cm.
- Contact prints from glass plate negatives, Series A:141-180: box no. 13-14, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Item 143: Twister, G Model, Draper Company, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A143. 1901-1916. Image depicts a view of a G Model twister manufactured by the Draper Company. The twister is photographed against a sheet, probably in an unknown mill, and is seen from the side rather than head-on. "Draper Company" is embossed on the piece on the floor, leaning against the machine. A twister is a machine for twisting together two or more separate ends, making either a ply yarn or a cable yarn, or for inserting additional twist in a single end. It is made with either a pin creel or beam creel; in this case, a pin creel, which can be seen on the top of the twister. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 20.25 x 25 cm.
  - Item 152: Houses on Bancroft Parkway, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A152. 1901-1916. Image depicts a view of Bancroft Parkway in Hopedale, Massachusetts Substantial two-story, wood-shingled houses line the unpaved road. Electric poles can be seen on the left-hand side of the road. Most of the houses have two chimneys and are duplexes, as Hopedale housing built for Draper Company employees was generally not larger than a duplex. See Item 157 and Item 163, in this folder, for other views of these houses. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 153: Close-up view of house on Bancroft Parkway, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Printed in 1974 from glass plate negative no.A153. 1901-1916. Image depicts a closer view of a house on Bancroft Parkway, done in the Dutch Colonial (or gambrel) style. The house is wood-shingled, has shutters on every window, and has two separate entrances in the front; it is most likely a duplex. (See Item 171, in this folder, for another view of this house, although lacking the bushes in the front yard.) A similar wood-shingled house can be glimpsed behind this one in the left background. These houses were built for Draper Company employees. See Item 172 and Item 175, in this folder, for other views of houses on Bancroft Parkway, and Item 166 for a view of the back yards of the houses on Bancroft Parkway. 25 x 20.25 cm.
  - Item 155: Two houses on Bancroft Parkway, black and white photograph (Box 2, Folder 2)